<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>python on AI Logs</title><link>https://ai.ragv.in/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on AI Logs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 [Raghava Dhanya](https://ragv.in) | [License](/license) |</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 21:36:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ai.ragv.in/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Go faster with Go: Golang for ML Serving</title><link>https://ai.ragv.in/posts/golang-for-machine-learning-serving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 21:36:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ai.ragv.in/posts/golang-for-machine-learning-serving/</guid><description>So the ask is to do 3 Million Predictions per second with as little resources as possible. Thankfully its one of the simpler model of Recommendation systems, Multi Armed Bandit(MAB). Multi Armed bandit usually involves sampling from distribution like Beta Distribution. That&amp;rsquo;s where the most time is spent. If we can concurrently do as many sampling as we can, we&amp;rsquo;ll use the resources well. Maximizing Resource utilization is the key to reducing overall resources needed for the model.</description></item><item><title>BPMN Pipeline Platform</title><link>https://ai.ragv.in/posts/bpmn-pipeline-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 20:54:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ai.ragv.in/posts/bpmn-pipeline-platform/</guid><description>One of my major work at Mu Sigma Labs was with BPMN based analytics automation/ pipeline platform. Based on an open source platform Activiti. I was the owner and developed, tested, maintained the platform. It served about 3k internal users and ran several critical reporting and data pipelines.
Technologies Used Java, Spring Boot as Backend. The platform itself supported scripting in Python, R for automation. Angular for Frontend.
BPMN Business Process Model and Notation (BPMN) is a standard for modeling business processes in a graphical notation.</description></item></channel></rss>